Guide to the Victor Remer Historical Archives of the Children's Aid Society 1836-2006 (bulk 1853-1947) MS 111
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI - Financial and Fund-Raising Records, 1853-1974
  - Subseries VI.4 - Volumes. Supplement, circa 1858-1963; 82 Linear feet
    - Cash Disbursements. 1930 (Offsite-box 1151, Volume 566)
    - Cash Disbursements. 1931 (Offsite-box 1153, Volume 570)
    - Cash Disbursements. 1934-1936 (Offsite-box 1151, Volume 564)
    - General Ledger #14. 1939-1941 (Offsite-box 1157, Volume 579)
    - General Ledger #15. 1942-1944 (Offsite-box 1157, Volume 580)
    - General Ledger #16. 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 1157, Volume 581)
    - General Ledger #17. 1948-1950 (Offsite-box 1158, Volume 582)
    - General Ledger #18. 1951-1953 (Offsite-box 1158, Volume 583)
    - General Ledger #19. 1954-1955 (Offsite-box 1158, Volume 584)
    - Special Appropriations (1938) (Offsite-box 1164, Volume 595)
    - Special Appropriations (1939) (Offsite-box 1164, Volume 596)
    - Special Appropriations (1940) (Offsite-box 1165, Volume 597)
    - Special Appropriations (1941) (Offsite-box 1165, Volume 598)
    - Special Appropriations (1942) (Offsite-box 1166, Volume 599)
    - Special Appropriations (1943) (Offsite-box 1166, Volume 600)
    - Special Appropriations (1944) (Offsite-box 1167, Volume 601)
    - Special Appropriations (1945) (Offsite-box 1167, Volume 602)
    - Special Appropriations (1946) (Offsite-box 1168, Volume 603)
    - Special Appropriations (1947) (Offsite-box 1168, Volume 604)
    - Special Appropriations (1948) (Offsite-box 1169, Volume 605)
    - Special Appropriations (1949) (Offsite-box 1169, Volume 606)
    - Special Appropriations (1950) (Offsite-box 1170, Volume 607)
    - Special Appropriations (1951) (Offsite-box 1170, Volume 608)
    - Special Appropriations (1952) (Offsite-box 1189, Volume 649)
    - Special Appropriations (1953) (Offsite-box 1189, Volume 650)
    - Special Appropriations (1954) (Offsite-box 1190, Volume 651)
    - Special Appropriations (1955) (Offsite-box 1190, Volume 652)
    - Special Appropriations (1956) (Offsite-box 1191, Volume 653)
    - Special Appropriations (1957) (Offsite-box 1191, Volume 654)
    - Special Appropriations (1958) (Offsite-box 1191, Volume 655)
    - Special Appropriations (1959) (Offsite-box 1192, Volume 656)
    - Special Appropriations (1960) (Offsite-box 1192, Volume 657)
    - Special Appropriations (1961) (Offsite-box 1193, Volume 658)
    - Cash Book. 1909 Feb-Sept (Offsite-box 1171, Volume 609)
    - Cash Book. 1910 Sept-1911 March, 1910-1911 (Offsite-box 1171, Volume 610)
    - Cash Book. 1911 April-Sept (Offsite-box 1172, Volume 611)
    - Cash Book. 1911 Oct-1912 Feb, 1911-1912 (Offsite-box 1172, Volume 612)
    - Cash Book. 1912 March-July (Offsite-box 1173, Volume 613)
    - Cash Book. 1912 August-1913 March, 1912-1913 (Offsite-box 1173, Volume 614)
    - Cash Book. 1913 March-Sept (Offsite-box 1174, Volume 615)
    - Cash Book. 1913 Oct-1914 March, 1913-1914 (Offsite-box 1174, Volume 616)
    - Cash Book. 1914 April-Sept (Offsite-box 1175, Volume 617)
    - Cash Book. 1914 Oct-1915 Sept, 1914-1915 (Offsite-box 1175, Volume 618)
      Page 286 includes an adjustment for the period, dated March 1916.
    - Cash Book. 1915 Oct-1916 June, 1915-1916 (Offsite-box 1176, Volume 619)
    - Cash Book. 1916 July-1917 June, 1916-1917 (Offsite-box 1176, Volume 620)
    - Cash Book. 1917 July-1918 June, 1917-1918 (Offsite-box 1177, Volume 621)
    - Cash Book. 1919 July-1920 June, 1919-1920 (Offsite-box 1177, Volume 622)
    - Cash Book. 1920 July-1921 June, 1920-1921 (Offsite-box 1178, Volume 623)
    - Cash Book. 1922 July-Oct (Offsite-box 1178, Volume 624)
    - Voucher Register. 1951 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1179, Volume 625)
    - Voucher Register. 1951 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1179, Volume 626)
    - Voucher Register. 1952 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1179, Volume 627)
    - Voucher Register. 1952 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1180, Volume 628)
    - Voucher Register. 1953 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1180, Volume 629)
    - Voucher Register. 1953 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1180, Volume 630)
    - Voucher Register. 1954 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1181, Volume 631)
    - Voucher Register. 1954 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1181, Volume 632)
    - Voucher Register. 1955 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1181, Volume 633)
    - Voucher Register. 1955 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1182, Volume 634)
    - Voucher Register. 1956 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1182, Volume 635)
    - Voucher Register. 1956 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1182, Volume 636)
    - Voucher Register. 1957 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1183, Volume 637)
    - Voucher Register. 1957 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1183, Volume 638)
    - Voucher Register. 1958 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1184, Volume 639)
    - Voucher Register. 1958 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1184, Volume 640)
    - Voucher Register. 1959 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1185, Volume 641)
    - Voucher Register. 1959 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1185, Volume 642)
    - Voucher Register. 1960 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1186, Volume 643)
    - Voucher Register. 1960 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1186, Volume 644)
    - Voucher Register. 1961 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1187, Volume 645)
    - Voucher Register. 1961 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1187, Volume 646)
    - Voucher Register. 1962 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1188, Volume 647)
    - Voucher Register. 1962 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1188, Volume 648)
    - Prepaid Insurance, 1944-1949 (Offsite-box 1193, Volume 659)
    - Insurance Register, 1955-1959 (Offsite-box 1194, Volume 660)
    - Security Ledger (Investments), 1959-1961 (Offsite-box 1194, Volume 661)
      Includes record of securities held 1959-61 and associated income received during the period.
    - Custodian Account (Investments), 1959-1961 (Offsite-box 1206, Volume 662)
    - Board Summary (Board, Clothing & Other Allowances). 1947-1949 (Offsite-volume 666)
    - Board Summaries (Board, Clothing & Other Allowances). 1950-1952 (Offsite-box 1195, Volume 667)
    - Board Book (Board, Clothing & Other Allowances). 1953-1955 (Offsite-box 1195, Volume 668)
    - Board Book (Board, Clothing & Other Allowances). 1956-1958 (Offsite-box 1196, Volume 669)
    - Board & Clothing Book (Board, Clothing & Other Allowances). 1959-1961 (Offsite-box 1196, Volume 670)
    - Summary of Expenses. 1948-1951 (Offsite-box 1197, Volume 671)
    - Summary of Expenses. 1952-1955 (Offsite-box 1197, Volume 672)
    - Summary of Expenses. 1956-1959 (Offsite-box 1197, Volume 673)
    - Expenditure Register. 1914 Oct-1916 June, 1914-1916 (Offsite-volume 663)
    - Expenditure Register. 1916 July-1917 June, 1916-1917 (Offsite-volume 664)
    - Expenditure Register. 1918 July-1919 June, 1918-1919 (Offsite-volume 665)
    - Expenditure Register. 1919 July-1920 June, 1919-1920 (Offsite-volume 674)
    - Expenditure Register. 1920 July-1921 June, 1920-1921 (Offsite-volume 675)
    - Expenditure Register. 1922 July-Sept (Offsite-volume 676)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1951 May-August (Offsite-box 1198, Volume 677)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1952 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1198, Volume 678)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1952 May-August (Offsite-box 1198, Volume 679)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1952 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1198, Volume 680)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1953 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1199, Volume 681)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1953 May-August (Offsite-box 1199, Volume 682)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1953 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1199, Volume 683)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1954 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1200, Volume 684)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1954 May-August (Offsite-box 1200, Volume 685)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1954 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1200, Volume 686)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1955 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1201, Volume 687)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1955 May-August (Offsite-box 1201, Volume 688)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1955 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1201, Volume 689)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1956 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1202, Volume 690)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1956 May-August (Offsite-box 1202, Volume 691)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1956 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1202, Volume 692)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1957 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1203, Volume 693)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1957 May-August (Offsite-box 1203, Volume 694)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1957 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1203, Volume 695)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1958 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1204, Volume 696)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1958 May-August (Offsite-box 1204, Volume 697)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1958 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1204, Volume 698)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1959 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1205, Volume 699)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1959 May-August (Offsite-box 1205, Volume 700)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1959 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1205, Volume 701)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1960 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1239, Volume 702)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1960 May-August (Offsite-box 1239, Volume 703)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1960 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1240, Volume 704)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1961 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1240, Volume 705)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1961 May-August (Offsite-box 1241, Volume 706)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1961 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1241, Volume 707)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1962 Jan-April (Offsite-box 1242, Volume 708)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1962 May-August (Offsite-box 1242, Volume 709)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1962 Sept-Dec (Offsite-box 1243, Volume 710)
    - Income Register. 1914 October-1917 June, 1914-1917 (Offsite-box 1206, Volume 711)
    - Income Register. 1959-1961 (Offsite-box 1154, Volume 573)
    - Income Analysis. 1932-1935 (Offsite-box 1206, Volume 712)
    - Income Analysis. 1936-1938 (Offsite-box 1207, Volume 713)
    - Income Analysis. 1939-1942 (Offsite-box 1207, Volume 714)
    - Income Analysis. 1952-1955 (Offsite-box 1207, Volume 715)
    - Income Analysis. 1956-1960 (Offsite-box 1208, Volume 716)
    - Income Analysis. 1961-1963 (Offsite-box 1208, Volume 717)
    - Cash Receipts. 1950-1952 (Offsite-box 1208, Volume 718)
    - Donations. 1909 Oct-1910 Sept, 1909-1910 (Offsite-box 1209, Volume 719)
    - Donations. 1910 Oct-1911 Sept, 1910-1911 (Offsite-box 1209, Volume 720)
    - Donations. 1911 Oct-1912 Sept, 1911-1912 (Offsite-box 1210, Volume 721)
    - Donations. 1913 Oct-1914 Sept, 1913-1914 (Offsite-box 1210, Volume 722)
    - Donations. 1914 Oct-1915 Sept, 1914-1915 (Offsite-box 1211, Volume 723)
    - Donations. 1915 Oct-1916 June, 1915-1916 (Offsite-box 1211, Volume 724)
    - Donations. 1916 July-1917 June, 1916-1917 (Offsite-box 1212, Volume 725)
    - Donations. 1918 July-1919 June, 1918-1919 (Offsite-box 1212, Volume 726)
    - Donations. 1919 July-1920 June, 1919-1920 (Offsite-box 1213, Volume 727)
    - Donations. 1920 July-1921 June, 1920-1921 (Offsite-box 1213, Volume 728)
    - Donations. 1921 July-1922 June; 1924 December, 1921-1922, 1924 (Offsite-box 1214, Volume 729)
      In addition to the volume's principal entries for the 1921-22 period, the volume also includes the records for 18-31 December 1924, forwarded from page 251 of the volume for July-Dec 1924.
    - Donations. 1922 June-1923 June, 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 1214, Volume 730)
    - Donations. 1923 July-1924 May, 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 1214, Volume 731)
      Includes several loose sheets with summaries for years from 1917-1925.
    - Donations. 1924 Dec-1925 Dec; 1926 Dec, 1924-1926 (Offsite-box 1215, Volume 732)
      The volume principally includes entries for 1925, but also includes a few opening entries from late December of 1924 and some "spillover" entries from late December 1926.
    - Donations. 1925 Dec-1926 Dec, 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 1215, Volume 733)
    - Donations. 1927 Jan-Dec (Offsite-box 1216, Volume 734)
    - Donations. 1929 Jan-Dec (Offsite-box 1216, Volume 735)
    - Donations. 1930 Jan-Dec (Offsite-volume 736)
    - Donations. 1931 Jan-1932 Jan, 1931-1932 (Offsite-volume 737)
    - Donations. 1932 Jan-Dec (Offsite-volume 738)
    - Donations. 1934 Jan-Dec (Offsite-box 1217, Volume 739)
    - Donations. 1935 Jan-Dec (Offsite-box 1217, Volume 740)
    - Donations. 1939 Jan-Dec (Offsite-volume 741)
    - Donations. 1940 Jan-Dec (Offsite-volume 742)
    - Donations. 1941 Jan-Dec (Offsite-volume 743)
    - Donations. 1936 Jan-Dec (Offsite-volume 744)
    - Donations. 1937 Jan-Dec (Offsite-volume 745)
    - Donations. 1938 Jan-Dec; 1939 Dec, 1938-1939 (Offsite-volume 746)
      The volume includes "spillover" entries for the final days of 1939 December.
    - Donations. 1943 Jan-June (Offsite-box 1244, Volume 747)
    - Donations. 1943 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1244, Volume 748)
    - Donations. 1944 Jan-July (Offsite-box 1245, Volume 749)
    - Donations. 1944 July-Dec (Offsite-box 1245, Volume 750)
    - Opera Benefit. 1937-1939 (Offsite-box 1246, Volume 751)
    - [Cash Journal]. 1902 October-1906 September, 1902-1906 (Offsite-box 1246, Volume 752)
    - Trial Balance. 1938-1942 (Offsite-box 1246, Volume 753)
    - Trial Balance. 1943-1947 (Offsite-box 1246, Volume 754)
    - [Bank Account Reconciliations]. 1951-1955 (Offsite-box 1246, Volume 755)
    - Donations, Special Campaigns. 1928 December-1931 March, 1928-1931 (Offsite-box 1246, Volume 756)
    - Journal #5 [Fund Investments], 1941-1948 (Offsite-box 1246, Volume 757)
    - [Payroll Summary?]. 1938-1942 (Offsite-box 1243, Volume 758)
    - Receipts & Donations / Cash Book. 1874 January-1880 December, 1874-1880 (Offsite-box 1218, Volume 759)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. Continuation of Charles Loring Brace Account Book?;see volume 79 for 1867-73 entries. See volume 125 for 1880-1885 entries.
    - [Cash Book]. 1868 Dec-1872 Feb, 1868-1872 (Offsite-box 1218, Volume 760)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. Appears to continue in volume 90.
    - [Cash Book]. 1870 March-1872 Feb, 1870-1872 (Offsite-box 1219, Volume 761)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated.
    - [Cash Book]. 1874 June-1876 March, 1874-1876 (Offsite-box 1219, Volume 762)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1876 April-1877 July, 1876-1877 (Offsite-volume 763)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1877 August-1878 July, 1877-1878 (Offsite-box 1220, Volume 764)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1880 July-1881 June, 1880-1881 (Offsite-box 1220, Volume 765)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1882 July-1883 July (Offsite-box 1221, Volume 766)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1884 August-1885 July (Offsite-box 1221, Volume 767)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1885 August-1886 July, 1885-1886 (Offsite-box 1222, Volume 768)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1886 August-1887 July (Offsite-box 1222, Volume 769)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1887 August-1888 July (Offsite-box 1223, Volume 770)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures].1888 August-1889 July (Offsite-box 1223, Volume 771)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1890 September-1891 August (Offsite-box 1224, Volume 772)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1891 September-1892 July (Offsite-box 1224, Volume 773)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1892 August-1893 June (Offsite-box 1225, Volume 774)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1893 July-1894 April (Offsite-box 1225, Volume 775)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1894 May-1895 February (Offsite-box 1226, Volume 776)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1895 March-October (Offsite-box 1226, Volume 777)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1895 November-1896 October; 1897 October (Offsite-volume 778)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. The pages run to 1896 October, but the last page shows as 1897 October 31, which is where next volume picks up. Not clear where 1986 Nov-1897 October is. Possibly the 1897 reference is an error.
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1897 November-1898 October (Offsite-volume 779)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1898 November-1899 September (Offsite-box 1227, Volume 780)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1900 October-1901 September (Offsite-box 1227, Volume 781)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1902 September-1903 September (Offsite-volume 782)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1904 October-1905 September (Offsite-volume 783)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1905 October-1906 September (Offsite-volume 784)
    - [ Receipts and Donations]. 1902 October-1903 September (Offsite-box 1228, Volume 785)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. I includes a monthly summary inside back cover.
    - [ Receipts and Donations]. 1904 October-1905 September (Offsite-box 1228, Volume 786)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. Includes a monthly summary inside back cover.
    - [Receipts and Donations]. 1905 October-1906 September (Offsite-box 1229, Volume 787)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. Iincludes a monthly summary inside back cover.
    - [Receipts and Donations]. 1906 October-1907 September (Offsite-box 1229, Volume 788)
    - [Donations]. 1908 October-1909 September (Offsite-box 1230, Volume 789)
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register]. 1914 October-1915 September (Offsite-box 1230, Volume 790)
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register; Income Receivables]. 1915 October-1916 June (Offsite-box 1231, Volume 791)
      Includes Poor Law Officers Accounts. The covers and spine are badly deteriorated.
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register; Income Receivables] 1917 July-1918 June (Offsite-box 1231, Volume 792)
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register; Income Receivables] 1918 July-1919 June (Offsite-volume 793)
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register; Income Receivables] 1919 July 1920 June (Offsite-box 1232, Volume 794)
      Includes Poor Law Officers Accounts, including a summary of outstanding balances as of 1920 June). The covers and spine are badly deteriorated.
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register; Income Receivables] 1920 July-1921 June (Offsite-box 1232, Volume 795)
    - [Expenditures Ledger] circa 1858 February-1868 December (Offsite-box 1233, Volume 796)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. Volume 57 with expenses for 1853-57 appears to be the preceding volume.
    - Industrial Schools. Special Donation Accounts. 1903-1907 (Offsite-box 1233, Volume 797)
    - [Expense Allocation by Facility, Emigration, etc.] 1903 October-1905 September (Offsite-box 1234, Volume 798)
    - [Expense Allocation by Facility, Emigration, etc.] 1905 October-1907 December (Offsite-box 1234, Volume 799)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1885 November-1887 October (Offsite-box 1235, Volume 800)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1892 November-1893 October (Offsite-box 1235, Volume 801)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1896 November-1897 October (Offsite-box 1236, Volume 802)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1897 October-1898 October (Offsite-box 1236, Volume 803)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1898 November-1899 October (Offsite-box 1236, Volume 804)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1899 October-1900 September (Offsite-box 1237, Volume 805)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1900 September-1901 September (Offsite-box 1237, Volume 806)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1901 October-1902 September (Offsite-box 1237, Volume 807)
- Series VII - Legal Records, circa 1861-1925
  This series consists of 1 box of documents relating to miscellaneous legal matters, in folders arranged chronologically circa 1861-1925, and one volume (a mostly handwritten compilation of laws relating to gifts to charitable agencies 1848-1893; date of compilation unknown). The documents are mainly legal instruments (agreements, contracts, bonds, licenses), requests or petitions for legislation, as well as a few reports and letters regarding legal issues, and copies of legislation effecting the CAS. The volume is listed after the boxes in the container list.
  - Copy of a petition to the N.Y. State Legislature: CAS requesting a share in the "School Fund" for CAS schools, circa 1861 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 1)
  - An Act providing for the county of NY to make up for the shortfall of the CAS for the year 1871, circa 1871 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 2)
  - Warrant in the case of two boys, Nicola Saraceno and Giuseppe Gallicano, giving custody of them to CAS, 1873 August 1 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 3)
  - NY State Senate bill: "An Act for the Protection of Factory Children and Other Persons", 1874 January 22 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 4)
  - Sheperds Fold vs. the Mayor: Lawsuit to repeal tax (2 documents), 1882 and undated (Offsite-box 37, Folder 5)
  - Arguments re: legality of appropriations from the Common School Fund to the industrial schools of the CAS, 1883 May 29 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 6)
  - State of NY, State Board of Charities, Laws of 1884, Chapter 438 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 7)
  - "An Act to Regulate the Employment of Women and Children in Manufacturing Establishments" - page from Laws of NY, 1886 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 8)
  - Legal opinion of Judge H.C. Van Vorst in justification of CAS charter amendment, transcribed excerpt from minutes, 1888 December 19 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 9)
  - Publishing contract between Charles Loring Brace and A.C. Armstrong & Son to publish "The Unknown God; or Inspiration Among Pre-Christian Races", 1890 April 30 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 10)
  - Legal opinion that CAS children are not "inmates" among other matters, 1895 March 13 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 11)
  - Joint letter by CAS and 6 other charities in opposition to bill giving too much power to State Board of Charities, and a copy of the bill, and a substitute bill proposed by charities, 1898 February 25 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 12)
  - Legal document: Bond: John J. McDonald to pay Julia G. Inness, 1900 January 18 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 13)
  - Legal Document: General Release, 1902 October 2 and 6 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 14)
  - Report on history of laws and policies relating to abandoned children, and a draft of same, by unknown CAS author for unknown audience, undated, post-1903 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 15)
  - "Protestant Children Under Catholic Care": a report by the CAS Probation Commission regarding probation legislation, undated, circa 1906 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 16)
  - Copies of agreements and receipts with the National Surety Co. guaranteeing againg diseased children becoming a public charge in Iowa and Nebraska, 1907, 1923, 1926 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 17)
  - Legal Document: General Release, 1908 September 30 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 18)
  - Legal document: 2 General Releases, 1918 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 19)
  - Legal document re: estate of Sarah H. Crosby and her real estate, 1914 March 31 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 20)
  - Agreements for the Endowment of Beds, 1919 December (Offsite-box 37, Folder 21)
  - CAS license to run child caring and placing agency in Lansing Michigan, undated, circa 1925 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 22)
  - Acts of the Legislature in Favor of the Children's Aid Society, 1848-1893 (Offsite-box 1046, Volume 262)
- Series VIII - Real Estate Records, circa 1869-1964
  Series VIII consists of 1 box and 1 oversize box of documents relating to CAS real estate, arranged chronologically 1873-1964, and 3 volumes [circa 1869]-1961. The documents in the boxes include deeds, leases, contracts, a small amount of correspondence, and architectural drawings.
  The first box (box 38) consists of folders arranged chronologically 1873-1964, including 3 folders related to work for the CAS by the architectural firm of Calvert Vaux & George Radford interfiled with the other real estate material. Some of the folders in this box include groups of leases, contracts or other documents related to a single property over a span of years, and these are arranged chronologically according to the first document in the folder.
  The second box (OS1) is an oversize box of 4 architectural drawings on drafting linen (3 exteriors, 1 cutaway) of the Rhinelander School by the firm of Vaux & Radford circa 1890. The drawings, numbered 7, 8, 9 and 12, appear to be part of a series of drawings, but the location of the remaining drawings is unknown.